





Summary

Jump to Section

Result-oriented Professional with 5 years of experience in IT Infrastructure Management, Cloud Mgration, Devops, CI/CD Pipelines, Software Troubleshooting, Computer Networking, Application Virtualization, Technology Management, Wware.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Work Experience

- Wipro LTD as Senior Project Engineer Jul 2015 to Jul 2015
 - 1.Setting up client?s infrastructure on AWS cloud platform. Implementing migration strategies using AWS services like VPC, IAM, EC2, ELB,ALB, RDS, S3, EKS, Route53, DR-Copy AMI to new AMI as a backup region.
 - 2.Creating end to end CI/CD Pipelines using Jenkins.
 - 3. Creating customized docker images to run client?s applications as a microservice.
 - 4. Managing microservice deployments in kubernetes platform.
 - 5.Installation of active directory, Creation of users and OU.
- 6. Installation and configuration of DHCP, DNS. Working in Domain environment.
- 7.Configuration of Exchange server outlook thunderbird used to send email from server to client. Creating mailbox for users.
- 8.Installations of PAC files on IIS Server and basis Troubleshooting on Proxyserver.Creating of PAC File with internal/External/Blocked Function.
- 9.Creation of new rule and PAC file in ZScaler. Creating URL category for cloud users and PAC file troubleshooting.
 10.Handling each single SR without failing.
- Wipro as Senior Project Engineer Jul 2015 to Till Date

AWS Devops Docker kubernetes Jenkins git github

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Electronics) from UNIVERSITY OF DELHI, DELHI in 2015

PG: M.Tech (Computers) from Vellore Institute of Technology in 2019

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: AWS

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
AWS		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Jenkins		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
DOCKER		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Windows System Administration		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
devops		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Cloud Computing		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
GIT		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
GitHub		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Active Directory		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Proxyserver		2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: Cloud Migration

Client: Genpact

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2015 - Till Date Project Location: Noida Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Role: Network/System Administrator Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Cloud Computing, Devops, Windows System Administration, Jenkins, Continuous Integration, Proxy Server, Docker, Github, GIT, AWS

Role Description: Cloud infrastruct mgmt:VPC, IAM, EC2, ELB,ALB, RDS, S3, EKS, Route53, DR- Copy AM to new AM as a backup region.

Jenkins, Devops, CICD, AD, DNS, DHCP, IIS, Zscaler PAC and Proxy

Project Details: 1.Setting up clients infrastructure on AWS cloud platform. Implementing migration strategies using AWS services like VPC, IAM, EC2, ELB, ALB, RDS, S3, EKS, Route53, DR-Copy AMI to new AMI as a backup region.

2.Creating end to end CI/CD Pipelines using Jenkins.

3. Creating customized docker images to run clients applications as a microservice.

4. Managing microservice deployments in kubernetes platform.

5.Installation of active directory, Creation of users and OU.

6. Installation and configuration of DHCP, DNS. Working in Domain environment.

7. Configuration of Exchange server outlook thunderbird used to send email from server to client. Creating mailbox for

8.Installations of PAC files on IIS Server and basis Troubleshooting on Proxyserver.Creating of PAC File with internal/External/Blocked Function.

9.Creation of new rule and PAC file in ZScaler. Creating URL category for cloud users and PAC file troubleshooting.

10. Handling each single SR without failing.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.